( FILM WHIRS )
Just one box ?
It 's for my office . It 's fragile .
Sissy .
( LOUD MUSIC THROUGH HEADPHONES ) - Hey , dude , headphones .
You 're gonna go deaf !
An autograph ?
- I just thought that ... - Are you kidding me ?
Ma 'am ?
- Sheriff . - Your husband around ?
MAN : Ashley ?
Ashley ?
Honey .
Sweetheart .
- What are you doing ? - Painting .
Yeah . I know . I think your mom wants your help unpacking .
I know .
So come outside .
You can finish your painting later .
I didn 't wanna move here .
I shouldn 't have to carry boxes .
We had to move here and we all have to help carry boxes .
Uh-uh . You wanted to move here .
No , I had to move here .
The new story I 'm writing is here .
Why can 't you just keep writing in the old house ?
'Cause I was gonna have to write college textbooks to pay for that old house .
- And I can 't do that . - Why not ?
'Cause I just can 't .
But I miss my school .
Well , you know what ?
The school here is supposed to be pretty great .
But I want my old one .
I know . How about this , all right ?
I 'll tell you what .
If we don 't like it here , once I sell my book , we 'll move back .
But only if we don 't like it here .
- Really ? - Really .
You promise ?
I promise . But you have to promise to try to like it here .
- I promise . - You do ? Now , my little artist .
What 's the number one rule ?
Paint only goes in the bedroom .
Where doesn 't it go ?
Anywhere else in the house .
Right . OK , now , come with me .
Move some boxes .
Sheriff 's here .
- Already ? - Play nice this time .
- I 'm always nice . - I 'm not kidding .
I 'm tired of driving five miles under the speed limit to get ticketed anyway .
Be nice .
Afternoon . Is there a problem ?
No , sir . Just a friendly visit .
I appreciate that . Ellison Oswalt .
I know who you are .
- So you 're not a fan . - No .
Well , what can I do for you ?
Well , not much , I expect , unless I can convince you
to load those boxes back on that truck and leave as soon as you 're able .
No , I don 't think so , but , you know what .
I do have a couple of extra copies of Kentucky Blood
if you want me to get one out and sign it for you .
No , thank you , sir .
Is it the writing ?
More a matter of content .
You don 't seem to care much for our profession .
Not everybody in your profession gets it right .
I 've read your books .
Neither do you .
- Look ... - You got it right in Kentucky Blood .
I 'll give you that . It 's a fine piece of writing .
But Cold Denver Morning , you got it wrong .
- Blood Diner ... - Look , that wasn 't my fault . All right ?
Your bad theory helped a killer go free .
You ruined people 's lives .
Now , this town doesn 't need that .
It needs to heal .
It needs to forget .
We sure don 't want that circus that you bring with you .
Well , there 's a missing girl involved here .
She ain 't missing . She 's dead .
Come on . You don 't know that .
If that girl is still alive , then it ain 't no miracle
and we ain 't ever gonna find her .
Then I guess we should just let it go , huh ?
You don 't think the town deserves an explanation ?
Something like this ... You can never explain something like this .
And if you were able to , the odds are you wouldn 't much care for the answer .
Now , we did our job . You 'll see that .
And this is just another waste of your time like your last two books .
If writing true crime has taught me one thing .
It 's that whenever an officer of the law tells me that I 'm wasting my time ,
it just means he thinks he 's wasting his .
That 's clever . You ought to write that down .
Well , I 'm gonna go out on a limb
and assume your department is not at my disposal ?
Well , what do you know ?
You can still get things right on occasion .
Oh , and ... I find this to be in extremely bad taste .
- What was all that about ? - The usual .
He wanted an autograph , but he left his copy at home .
- He 'll be back later . - That bad ?
- Mm-hm . - Why was he pointing at the house ?
Ellison , we didn 't move in a few houses down from a crime scene again , did we ?
- Tracy ... - No , just don 't say anything .
If we did , I don 't wanna know about it .
- We didn 't . - You promise ?
I promise .
Here . Make yourself useful , Kitchen .
It 's gonna be good here , OK ? You 'll see .
( CHILDREN ARGUING )
( BANGING )
Shit .
Oh , shit .
You gotta be kidding me .
Family Hanging Out , ' 11 ?
Barbeque , ' 79 ?
I 've also got noodles and fortune cookies .
Enjoy , kids . We 're not likely to be able to eat out much this time .
- Oh ! - Why not ?
- You know why . - I don 't .
We haven 't sold the old house yet .
Once it 's gone , well be able to afford a few extra things .
Then sell it already .
Lower the price if you have to .
We 've already lowered it as much as we can .
The market 's terrible .
Once we 're not paying two mortgages , we 'll be fine .
And once I sell my new book , we 'll be on Easy Street .
Is the story a good one this time ?
Yeah , it 's good . Of course it is .
- Will you show me where it happened ? - Trevor .
I 'm old enough to know about this stuff .
No , youre not . Even I 'm not old enough to know about this stuff .
Your father writes about terrible , terrible things .
I shouldn 't be writing about it ?
That 's not what I meant .
That 's the way you said it .
I 'm gonna hear about it at school anyway .
Kids 'll all hate me again and tell me nonstop what happened .
Hey , nobody hates you .
I might as well hear it from you .
Are you listening to this ?
Yes . I 'm listening .
Let 's at least make sure your office stays locked .
It 's one thing to hear about it , another to see it .
I don 't want him walking in again . He 's 12 .
- Mom , he knows how old I am . - Hey , stop it .
- What 's the first rule ?
ALL : - Never go in Dad 's office .
And what 's the rule ?
- Always lock Dad 's office . - That 's right .
And I don 't wanna hear another thing about why we 're here , from anybody .
Yeah .
You didn 't brush your teeth .
- No. not yet . - You 're not coming to bed ?
No , I thought I 'd set up my office first and get started .
How long is it gonna be ?
Just an hour or two .
No , I mean ... how long are we here for this time ?
Oh , God ' I don 't know . It could be along one .
I liked it better when you were writing fiction .
( CHUCKLES )
Nobody likes my fiction .
Maybe you should try again .
I can 't do this without you by my side .
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry .
I 'm on your side .
I just wanna see you enjoying your work again .
When you 're happy ... we 're all happy .
I just need another hit , that 's all .
- Just one more . - I just ...
What ?
- You know I 'm behind you on this . - I know .
But that 's not what you were gonna say .
What were you gonna say ?
Kentucky Blood was ten years ago .
And ?
And ... what if that was your 15 minutes ?
OK , what if it was ?
If it was , you can 't just spend the rest of your life chasing after it .
If you miss out on these years with the kids , you won 't get them back .
I just need one more chance , that 's all , one more .
- OK. good . - I got a good feeling about this .
But , Ell , I don 't think I can do this again .
- Honey , you 're not gonna have to . - No . I mean it .
If this goes sour like last time .
I 'll take Trevor and Ashley and go back home to my sister 's .
- Is that fair ? - Yes .
But it 's not gonna go sour .
Good . Now go kick some arse .
What the hell ? Let 's do this .
All right .
( FILM WHIRS )
( SIGHS )
Why would you film it ?
( DOOR CREAKS )
Daddy , I can 't find the bathroom .
Come here . Come on . Come on . We 'll get you ...
Thank you , Daddy .
Look at all these new paintings .
You 're really getting good .
Thank you . Maybe one day I 'll paint something really good .
Then I 'll be famous like you .
I 'm sure you will , princess .
- All right , get some sleep . - OK .
- And Daddy ? - Yes ?
Are you gonna write a really good book this time so we can go home ?
I 'm gonna write the best book that anyone 's ever read .
( RINGING TONE )
MAN : - Operator . - Yeah , King County Police , please .
- Is this an emergency ? - Yes , yes , it is .
WOMAN : King County Police Department .
How may I direct your call ?
King County Police Department .
Hello ?
All right .
You came back and left the box .
Why ?
( THUDDING )
( DOOR CREAKS ) - Dammit , Ashley .
Ashley ?
( CREAKING )
( FLOORBOARDS CREAK )
( SCREECHES )
Trevor ! Trevor , Trevor , Trevor , hey , hey !
Wake up . Trevor , wake up , all right ?
Hey , hey , hey . Hey , wake up .
Wake up , all right ?
OK , OK . Come on , come on .
- Oh , my God , is he OK ? ( SCREAMING DROWNS OUT SPEECH )
Come on , open up .
Here we go . Come outside .
Hey , hey . Hey , hey , all right ?
Hey , hey , hey , wake up .
Come on , come on , come on , wake up .
Wake up , wake up , wake up .
Trevor , wake up for me , all right ? Hey , hey , hey .
Look at the stars . Trevor . Trevor , Trevor .
- Why are we outside ? - All right , bud . OK .
You were having a bad dream , OK ?
One of those night terrors .
Just go back to sleep .
I thought these were over .
It 's just the stress of the move .
I found him in one of the moving boxes .
Poor baby .
He 'll be all right in a few hours .
Oh . Oh , Tracy . I ...
What is it ? What 's the matter ?
I wanna ... I wanna tell you something .
OK .
I 'm just really sorry .
It 's not your fault .
Come on . It 's cold .
Let 's go inside .
I was in a box ?
You were in a box .
I don 't remember any of that .
It 's not the strangest place we 've ever found you .
Please don 't talk about the dryer .
Are we talking about the time we found Trevor trying to pee in the dryer ?
- God , Mom , no . - I 'm sorry , honey .
I thought that 's what you were talking about .
Did Trevor try to pee in the dryer again ?
- Mom . - No . Your brother had a night terror .
- Is that like a bad dream ? - Kind of .
ASHLEY : Oh , I think I had one of those .
No , a night terror is a special kind of bad dream .
We would have remembered if you had one .
Don 't do that . You can sit right here .
So , Ashley , you excited about your first day at the new school ?
- What about you ? - I guess .
It 's nice to see you 're both so enthusiastic about our adventure .
- Stop it . - Hey , you two stop it . Stop it .
Be the bigger person .
Are you gonna take ' em ?
Yeah , I 've got some errands to run .
I figured I 'd get the lay of the land and let you get some work done .
Eat up . You 're running late .
You heard your mother .
Grab some road breakfast and skedaddle .
- I left you a fresh pot of coffee . - Thanks .
Have a nice morning with your murder victims .
- Yes. dear . - Come on .
Trevor , where 's your notebook ?
It should be in my backpack .
Can you see it in there ?
( FILM WHIRS )
Oh , fuck .
That 's it . OK .
" Super 8 film was first released in 1966 by Eastman Kodak . "
OK .
Ah !
( CAR PULLS UP )
TRACY : Trevor , don 't walk away from me .
Ashley , close the door .
Trevor , what on earth were you thinking ?
TREVOR : I 'll tell you again .
I wasn 't thinking .
TRACY : That 's your problem .
You don 't think .
You wanna be treated like an adult , but you don 't act like one .
You and Dad do lots of thinking .
If you did , we wouldn 't be here .
You don 't know what you 're talking about .
I know more than you .
Go to your room !
- I don 't wanna see you until dinner . - Fine .
- What happened ? - Mom 's overreacting .
Your son is acting out again .
What did he do ?
You 're automatically taking her side ?
Hey , stop it . What did you do ?
I drew a picture .
A picture with a permanent marker on the classroom whiteboard .
- Oh , God . Trevor ? - Tell him what you drew .
- I drew a tree . - With four people hanging from it .
Go to your room , Trevor .
I need to speak to your father .
His first day at school , Ellison ,
and he 's already hearing the grisly details of your mystery ?
What did he hear ?
Exactly what he drew .
That your book is about a family that was hung .
- Christ , Ellison . - But that 's all he heard ?
That 's not enough ?
Look , I 'm sorry he had to find out like this , all right ? I am .
But , come on , it was bound to happen .
Really ? That 's your response ?
You think that makes it OK ?
No , it doesn 't make it OK. all right ?
Nothing about what happened to these people is OK .
But bad things happen to good people
and they still need to have their story told .
They deserve that much .
You 're a real man of the people .
Oh , come ...
I 'm putting the kids to bed .
Kiss them good night for me .
- You 're getting good work done ? - Yeah .
Good . Please keep the door closed .
( SIGHS )
OK , 1998 . St Louis murders .
New details today in the grisly murders
of a local family found earlier this week .
Police have released this photo of Christopher Miller ,
the missing 13-year-old son of William and Penny Miller .
The Millers , woman with their younger son ,
were found stabbed inside their home ,
and police now are asking for any information
that could lead to Christopher 's return or the apprehension of any suspects
involved in this vicious multiple murder and child abduction .
( FLOORBOARDS CREAK )
( READS SEMI-ALOUD )
( LOUD BANG )
( CLATTERING )
( LOUD BANG ) ( YELLS )
( YELLS )
Family Hanging Out .
Pool Party .
Barbecue .
Sleepy Time .
( CREAKING )
Really , I 'm fine .
I 'd prefer to take you down to the hospital . You should get stitches .
Can 't force you , though .
Yeah , and I 'm not gonna go .
The bleeding 's stopped for now , but if it starts again
or if there 's any more swelling , call a doctor immediately .
- Thank you . Appreciate it . - OK .
- This way . - So ... let 's go see this hole .
So you say you heard a loud thump and footsteps in the attic
after the power went out ?
Yes .
- But the ladder wasn 't down ? - No , it wasn 't .
It 's not possible to close it from inside the attic ?
No .
So how would an intruder get up there ?
I didn 't say anyone was up there .
I said it sounded like there was an intruder .
I did see a small snake , though .
Snakes don 't have feet .
You know , I 'm ... I 'm guessing that you got squirrels .
With , you know , way in and out up there
and all the power gone off in the neighbourhood .
I bet they got spooked from the sound of everything shutting down at once .
- You know how they are . - Not really .
- I 'm not really a squirrel guy . - Really ?
I did kill a scorpion when we first moved in here. though ,
so maybe I should get an exterminator .
Scorpions have feet .
but you wouldn 't hear ' em like you would squirrels .
Well , Officer , thank you very much .
It 's ... I will ... If there 's anything else I can do for you ...
Actually , there is . I left my copy of Kentucky Blood down at the station .
It 'd really mean a lot to me if you signed a copy .
I got a few extra copies in my office .
Thank you so much .
That 's so great .
Wow . Do you know what ?
This is like one of them FBI profiler 's offices .
You got a map with pictures connected with yarn and everything .
Deputy . I need you to step outside .
This is my private office . I 'm serious .
- Just wait outside . - Mr Oswalt. listen .
You know there 's a page in your books
where you always say nice things about all the people that helped you out ?
- The acknowledgements ? - Yeah. well ...
Yeah , and in each one there 's always like a line that says , you know .
" I couldn 't have done this without the tireless efforts
of Deputy So And So from the local police department . "
Right .
Well , you know , I could be like ...
you know , your Deputy So And So , you know , if you don 't already have one .
Yeah , there are a few things you could do for me , actually .
- Really ? - Yeah. this could be perfect .
- Do you have a notepad ? - Um ...
- Yes . - All right . Do you need a pen ?
Yes .
I need the street address of a crime .
In 1998 , St Louis , a family was stabbed to death .
They had their throats out .
It was a pretty ugly affair .
I also need any details you can get me on another murder ,
1979 , a family was burned alive ,
parked inside their own car , in their own garage .
- What city ? - I don 't know .
All I have is the year and the method of execution .
Hmm . You think that the two cases are related ?
Oh , no , no . I 'm just doing research .
OK . I can definitely get this for you .
I gotta wait till the sheriff leaves the office , but I will get it .
Thank you very much , Deputy So And So .
- I 'm sorry . - For what ?
I was angry at Trevor today and I took it out on you .
No , don 't be sorry .
I know the move 's been hard for you .
- I 'm trying , Ell . I really am . - I know .
I just want you here with me , that 's all .
I 've always been with you .
And I 'm with you now .
Pleased to have Ellison Oswalt on our programme .
His new book is called Kentucky Blood .
Good to have you on .
Thanks for having me . A real pleasure .
HOST : Man , I got into this .
This is pretty graphic stuff .
So let me star ?
by asking why you spend so much time
investigating such grisly content ?
Fame and money ? No , I 'm just kidding .
The honest answer is that I 'm really driven by a sense of injustice .
When I think about the awful things that happened to these people
and that those responsible were never even identified , let alone caught ...
I mean , I knew when I started this particular case
that I might stumble on a few things that maybe somebody 'd overlooked .
HOST : Might ? No , you in fact did uncover some additional information
that the cops had overlooked .
Well , look , first off , there are a lot of good police officers out there
and I don 't wanna in any way disparage what they do , right ?
But in police work getting something wrong means ruining people 's lives .
Good crime writing can set things right .
So , ultimately , what feels better ?
Seeing justice done or seeing your book , Kentucky Blood ,
number one on the New York Times bestseller list ?
The justice , without question .
I 'd rather cut my hands off than write a book for fame or money .
( SIGHS )
- Are you making Daddy his coffee ? - Yes .
Can I help ? I wanna bring it to him .
Sure , honey , but we have to make it just right .
He 's very particular about his coffee .
Brought you your coffee , Daddy .
Oh , thank you , sweetheart .
( RINGTONE ) - Oh .
- Yeah , hello . DEPUTY : - Hey , Mr Oswalt .
Hey , Deputy So And So .
I 'm sorry to get back to you so fate in the day .
I couldn 't make the call from the office . You know , the sheriff .
- Yeah , I understand .
- But I got what you asked about .
There was a Martinez family in Sacramento , California ,
that died in their garage in 1979 , their car was set on fire .
One of their sons , nine years old , they never found him .
- Do you have the street address ?
- It 's 8224 Billington , Sacramento .
And what about St Louis ?
The address of the house where the Miller murders occurred is
2976 Piedmont Way , St Louis .
That is excellent . 29 ... Wait , did you say 2976 , like 29-76 ?
Yeah . Does that mean something to you ?
No , no , it doesn 't . No .
Thank you . Thank you . Deputy .
Before the Stevensons moved here .
They lived where the Miller family murders happened ?
Holy shit .
( DOOR CREAKS )
( FILM WHIRS )
Ashley ?
Trevor ?
Oh , my God . Is he OK ?
I found him outside .
We have to put a lock on his door .
It 's way worse than it was .
I 'll call the doctor in the morning .
You stay with him .
I left something outside .
( DOG GROWLS )
( GROWLS )
Good dog . Good dog .
I don 't wanna hurt you .
I just wanna get my bat
so if you come at me , I can bash your head in , OK ?
That 's fine . You keep it .
- You OK ? - Yeah , I 'm fine , fine .
Trevor 's too old to still be having these .
He was supposed to have outgrown them by now .
- He 's all right . He 's OK . - Just stop .
- Stop what ? - Drop the book .
We can pack up , get out of town and never look back .
Why , ' cause he 's having some night terrors ?
It 's more than that .
He 's never been this bad .
You 've never been this bad .
What are you talking about ?
You 've been at this book less than a week and you 're already a mess .
You never crack into the whisky this early and this often .
- You 're saying I 'm a drunk ? - No .
I 'm saying there 's something you aren 't telling me ,
something that 's eating you up , and it seems to be getting to Trevor as well .
Somethings different this time .
Yeah , you wanna know what it is ?
How much do you wanna know ?
I wanna know why you 're different .
I 'm different because I 've never been onto something this big before .
Do you remember how it was when I was writing Kentucky ?
- I remember . - This is much bigger than that ! Much !
I am talking about a potentially important work here .
I 'm talking about a mega hit .
This could be my In Cold Blood .
A movie deal , talk show circuit , right ?
A national book award .
More money than we could ...
We could live wherever we wanted to .
I don 't care about any of that .
You do . Everybody does .
- I 'm just ... - This is my shot , Tracy .
You 're just what ?
I 'm just worried about you .
Well , don 't be .
Nothing is wrong .
Then why did you come in white as a ghost ?
Because I saw a dog , OK ?
- A dog ? - A very big dog , like Cujo big .
I mean , I 'd never seen him before . He 's like ...
Did you get rid of him ?
Yeah , he 's gone .
Listen , I just need a little more time . OK ?
I promise it 's worth it .
Every minute that we 're here , we 're a minute closer to that happy ending
that we always dreamed of .
We 're almost there .
OK ?
- Deputy . - Mr Oswalt , these came in this morning .
I had a few of the pertinent files pulled for you and had ' em faxed over .
- Really ? - Yeah .
- Thanks . - No problem .
Do you think I could come in for a second ?
Uh ... Yeah. sure .
- Thanks . - Come on , just here .
Look , I ... I know what you must think of me .
Some small-town deputy that 's starstruck with the famous writer .
But I 'm not some local moron .
I didn 't say you were a ... you know .
I have a degree in criminology .
I 've taken my fair share of forensic science courses .
I also know a series of connected murders when I see one , Mr Oswalt .
- Look ... - We missed something . I get that .
But if you want me to run interference for you while you get this worked out .
I gotta be in the loop just a little bit .
You really wanna help ?
It 's my home , Mr Oswalt .
What happened here happened to all of us .
All right . Come here .
Who is that ?
I don 't know .
That 's what I 'm hoping to find out .
- You think these are serial murders ? - Maybe .
More ritualized than necessarily serial .
But really spread out .
And not just regionally but over time .
The first one dates back to the ' 60s .
- The 1960s ? - Yeah .
That would put the guy , what , in his 70s ?
- Yeah. or his 60s . - Yeah , I ...
- I don 't know . - Well , look at the methodology .
Toxicology reports. some cases the killer drugged his victims .
- With what ? - Well , they couldn 't tell for sure .
But by drugging them , the killer removes his need to overpower them .
Here he used a tree branch to do the heavy lifting .
In Sacramento he lit a family on fire .
In St Louis he slit their throats .
- The first family he drowned . - Drowning ? You ...
You never said anything about anyone being drowned .
The only other significant link between the murder cases
is that in each instance the killer murdered the entire family except one .
A child which he took with him .
That and this symbol appears in several of the crime scenes .
That looks like something from out of the occult .
Look ' you might wanna call the university .
There 's a professor over there . Professor Jonas .
He 's an occult crime expert
and the state police bring him in on some of the ... the weirder stuff .
I think this qualifies .
( SIGHS ) So where do you think that drowning happened ?
That 's what I need you to find out .
OK .
( RINGING )
- Professor Jonas ? - Yes .
Hello . Hey , thank you for getting back to me so quickly .
I appreciate that .
Of course , I 'm a really big fan .
I 'm flattered that you emailed .
Once I saw the photos that you sent ,
I knew exactly what cases you were studying .
Wait . How would you know what cases I was looking at ?
The symbol that you sent me is ... isn 't a pentagram .
It 's not something that you would see teenagers
or a Norwegian black metal band paint on a wall in goat 's blood to be edgy .
- Right . - Or to piss off the Christians ..
No , this is a little bit more obscure than that .
I know the one in the hallway ,
that 's from the late ' 90s in St Louis .
The other one , the ... the car hood ,
that is from Sacramento , that 's about 30 years ago .
Tell me about the one in Sacramento .
It 's a symbol associated with the worship of a pagan deity .
A deity ? What kind of deity ?
A very obscure one , dating back to Babylonian times .
Named Bughuul , the eater of children .
- Did you say eater ?
- Yes , of children .
Thank you , Jessica .
The crimes that you 're dealing with .
They all have the element of a missing child , correct ?
Yes . Yeah . That 's correct .
Well , Bughuul eats children .
Now , the fragments of stories that have survived ,
they all revolve around him needing the souls of human children to survive .
Now , each story involves a different way
that he lures or tricks these children away from the physical world
and traps them in his own netherworld
and he consumes their souls over time .
Now , any worship of this deity would include a blood sacrifice
or the wholesale eating of a child .
So you 're saying the person that made this symbol is ... is eating children ?
Well , that would fit the stories .
Of course , the few times that this symbol has shown up ,
none of the crimes have been related in any way to any of this .
So this might be more of a cult initiation
rather than , you know , the actual actions of any one man .
There 's been another one , hasn 't there ?
I think so , yes .
Tell me everything you can .
( FILM WHIRS )
( DOOR BANGS )
( LIGHT THUD )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKS )
( FILM WHIRS )
Shh .
I appreciate you coming by , Officer .
Oh , yeah , it 's not a problem at all .
So we 're becoming friends . right ?
I ... I suppose , yeah .
I mean , I can trust you , right ?
Yeah , absolutely .
So if I were to ask you something in earnest .
You wouldn 't read too much into it ?
Um ... All right .
Was there anything ... weird about the Stevensons ?
No complaints from them about anything ... strange ?
No , not to my knowledge .
The investigators. did they notice anything odd or inexplicable
about the house , any ... any weird stories ?
No .
Mr Oswalt. is there something that you wanna tell me ?
Clearly something happened and you wanna talk to somebody about it , right ?
Yeah .
OK , well , does your wife know about it ?
Wait .
Does she know whose house this is ... was ?
( LAUGHS )
Oh , man . Oh , that is a conversation that I would not wanna be around for .
- No , me neither . - I 'm sorry .
So ... So , what , you saw something weird , heard something spooky in the house ?
- Yes . Precisely . - What exactly ?
Now ...
I don 't believe in any , you know , stuff .
Stuff ? You mean the supernatural , the metaphysical , the paranormal .
- That type of stuff ? - Right .
Right . Of course you don 't .
You never would have moved into a crime scene if you did .
But here we are having this conversation .
Yeah , but ... but there was ...
there was none of that , you know , none of that with the Stevensons , huh ?
No . In the short amount of time that the Stevensons lived here ,
they never called the police , they never had the police called on them
or reported anything bizarre that came up in the investigation .
- Do you wanna know what I think ? - Yes .
( SIGHS )
I think that you moved yourself into the house of murder victims
and immediately set about trying to put yourself in their head space .
I also think that you 've begun discovering things about this case
that go to darker places than you were prepared for .
I also think that every time that I 've been to your house .
There 's a whisky bottle that doesn 't appear to be neglected .
- No , no , no . I ... - Mr Oswalt. listen . I don 't . I don 't ...
I 'm not saying that you have a drinking problem . I don 't think that .
Nor do I think that you 're making any of this up ...
- No ! - ... to get attention .
What I do think is that ... that you are under so much stress .
You 've put yourself under so much stress .
That your mind is trying to process all of it at once .
So you don 't believe any of that otherworldly stuff , right ?
Are you kidding me ?
I believe in all that stuff .
I ... I wouldn 't sleep one night in this place . Are you nuts ?
Four people were hung by their necks in the tree in your backyard
and that little girl is probably God knows wherever .
- OK . - I 'm ... I 'm sorry .
You know what ?
You should try and get out more , Mr Oswalt , try to clear your head .
Total honesty ?
Last night I thought something was in the house
and I woke up on the couch holding a baseball bat .
Well ... I guess if I thought something was in my home at night .
I 'd be a little bit freaked out too .
But , listen , Mr Oswalt , if you sleep in this house .
It 's just gonna do terrible things to your head .
TRACY : Ellison !
- Ellison ! - What 's going on ?
Your daughter thought there wasn 't room on her walls for her new painting .
- Ashley ! - No , that 's not it .
What did we talk about ?
We only gave you one rule .
It was a big deal for us to let you paint on your walls .
What 's the rule , Ashley ?
Paint only goes in the bedroom .
And what makes you think you can paint out here ?
I wanted to paint her picture , but she didn 't want it in my room
because that used to be her brother 's room .
What ? Who are you talking about ?
- Stephanie . - Who 's Stephanie ?
She used to live here .
She 's the one Daddy 's writing his book about .
Ashley , go to your room and shut the door .
What the hell were you thinking ?
Did you think I wouldn 't find out ?
Shh . Of course I knew you were gonna find out eventually , OK ?
But don 't blame me for not telling you .
You never wanted to know .
Don 't try and pin this on me .
I asked you ! I asked you if we were living near the house !
You asked me if we were living two houses down from a crime scene .
- Don 't you dare ! - I said no .
We never should have come here !
Tracy , nobody died here .
It 's not like were sleeping where somebody was killed
or they had to wipe blood off the walls for the open house .
You 're saying it didn 't happen here ?
No . It happened in the backyard .
Oh , that is so sick !
God. you think that makes a difference ?
- It does . - No , Ellison . It doesn 't .
You have done some crazy shit in the past .
But this definitely takes the cake .
My God. what on earth possessed you to move here ?
We 've never been this broke before .
That 's no excuse .
This place came on the market .
It was a steal .
Gee , I wonder why .
So what Trevor drew last week , that happened here ?
Yes .
The previous owners of this home were hung from a tree in our backyard ?
- Yes . - That is so sick . Ellison .
And you let our little girl play back there ?
Why shouldn 't I ?
Our son is having night terrors
and drawing pictures of this crime at school .
And our daughter just painted a dead girl on our wall .
She 's missing .
Technically she 's missing .
I don 't wanna hear about technicalities .
Do you understand what you 've done ,
the kind of jeopardy you 've put your children in , your marriage ?
Yes , I do !
Is there anything you won 't do for your goddamn book ?
Apparently not . I guess this is all worth it to you .
- It 's worth it . - Putting your family at risk .
Risk of what ? Of more paintings ?
Don 't . Your daughter ...
My daughter has a father who loves her ,
who is always around , who encourages her to be herself .
The worst thing that has ever happened to her
is one time she moved into a house where a family was killed .
She found out about the murders , so she felt sorry for the little girl .
So she painted a fucking picture !
That 's what she does .
It 's what she always has done .
That 's it ? That 's all you have to say ?
What else do you want from me ?
How about a home where we feel safe , Ellison ?
How about neighbours that don 't hate us
in a town where I can buy groceries without getting strange looks ?
How about a life that doesn 't involve our kids
drawing and painting the sick details of some horrific tragedy
or working out their deep-seated anxieties
by doing bizarre shit in the night ?
How about that ?
Would that be OK ?
I can give all that to you , I can !
Just when I finish the book !
This book isn 't for us .
It 's for you .
Tracy , don 't say that . That 's not true .
It is true .
There are plenty of other ways you can provide for this family .
Doing what ? Teaching ?
Editing journalism textbooks ?
Don 't you understand that writing is what gives my life meaning ?
These books are my legacy .
I have always supported you doing what you love , Ellison .
But writing isn 't the meaning of your life .
You and me , right here , this marriage ' that 's the meaning of your life .
And your legacy , that 's Ashley and Trevor .
Your kids are your legacy .
- Did I get Daddy in trouble ? - No , sweetie .
Your daddy got Daddy in trouble .
- I 'm sorry I painted on the wall . - I know .
You get a good night 's sleep .
WOMAN ON VIDEO : So here 's the book I wrote proving it , right ?
ELLISON : Exactly .
WOMAN : Kidding aside , would you want a family ?
Is that in the cards ?
ELLISON : I don 't know .
If you 'd asked me a year ago , I might have said no , never , I 'm a career man .
But you know how it goes .
You meet someone. you get a little older .
All of a sudden , your career doesn 't seem to matter so much .
You want kids. you start to see other people with kids and think " I want that "
and then you wonder " Is he gonna look like me ?
Is she gonna look like her ? "
You paint rooms in your head and ...
Time for bed .
( GRUNTS )
( FILM WHIRS )
( STATIC BUZZES )
What is happening ?
( FILM WHIRS )
Shit .
( FLOORBOARD CREAKS )
What the hell are you doing ?
We have to leave here .
What 's the matter ?
What 's happened ?
You were right .
I made a mistake .
We should have never come to this house .
We have to leave now .
Ell , you 're freaking me out here .
Get the kids , pack the car .
We have to leave .
Go !
Honey , slow down .
I just wanna get on the highway .
I wanna put as much road between us and this town as we can , OK ?
OK .
Where are we going , Daddy ?
We 're going home , honey .
Home , home , like you promised ?
Yeah . Home , like I promised .
What about our stuff ?
We 're gonna call the movers in the morning , all right ?
It 's OK .
- Evening , Oswalts . - Sheriff .
- Licence and registration . - Oh . God .
Driving pretty fast for this time of night .
don 't you think ?
Anything I ought to know about ?
Just trying to take your advice , that 's all .
Which advice would that be ?
Leave town and never look back .
- You weren 't bullied away or anything ? - I 'm sorry ?
What I mean is , I don 't wanna be reading in your book
that angry town folks chased you out of here .
If you 've been mistreated , I wanna know about it .
There isn 't gonna be any book .
No book ?
No , sir .
Well. then .
I don 't see any reason for me to have your autograph .
Just one more favour .
Hold it under 60 till you cross the county line .
Until you 're somebody else 's problem .
Yes , sir .
Did you mean that ?
About the book ? Yeah .
You promise ?
I promise .
Let 's go home .
( LOUD ROCK MUSIC )
This goes in the office , right in there on the right .
( RINGTONE )
Hey , Ell , 10 bucks says Trevor sleeps through the night .
No , I 'm not taking that bet .
( EMAIL ALERT )
( RINGING )
Mr Oswalt , sorry it took so long to get back to you .
There 's been so little written on Bughuul
that no one has actually bothered to scan any of this material before .
- Well , what am I looking at ?
- You 're looking at an engraving .
An old sketch from the Dark Ages .
And fragments of a deteriorated fresco .
There isn 't a lot left .
Everything else has been destroyed .
- Why ? - Well , superstition .
Early Christians believed that Bughuul actually lived in the images themselves
and that they were gateways into his realm .
- Gateways ? - Yes .
The ancient Church believed that he would take possession
of those who saw the images and cause them to do terrible mings ,
or in some cases he could even abduct the viewer into the images themselves ,
Children exposed to the images
were especially vulnerable to Bughuul 's possession and / or abduction .
- What if you destroyed ' em ?
- Sorry . I don 't follow .
If you destroyed the images with a fire , what would happen then ?
What , do you mean literally or in the stories ?
In the stories if an image was destroyed ,
then the gateway would be closed
and Bughuul would no longer have access to this world , right ?
Mr Oswalt , what kind of book are you writing exactly ?
I don 't know .
I 'm not even sure I have a book any more .
- But thank you for your time . - Anytime .
( RINGTONE )
All right .
- You know what time it is ?
- I know . I 'm sorry .
But I 've been trying to call you all day .
- What 's the problem ?
- OK , the problem is that you moved .
How is that a problem ?
I was compiling all of the data that you had me collecting
and once I started putting it together into a nice readable package .
I saw the connection , it was obvious .
- What was it ?
- The dates , the addresses .
Each family that you had me look up
had previously lived in the house where one of the earlier murders took place .
Each family ? All five of them ?
Yes , and when you put them in chronological order ,
you can actually draw a line from murder to murder to murder .
OK , we knew that the Stevensons previously lived
in the same St Louis house where the Millers had their throats cut ,
Before the Miller family was killed ,
the Millers lived in the same house in Orange County
where the De Luzio lawn massacre occurred .
Guess where the De Luzios lived before they moved to Orange County ?
Sacramento where the Martinez family was burned in their garage ?
Exactly . The pattern goes back to the 1966 Oregon drownings .
Listen , Mr Oswalt , you just moved out of the last house in line .
If this guy is still out there ,
you not only just sped up his timeline , you put yourself in it .
Thanks , Deputy .
Stephanie .
It 's the missing kids .
( GROANS )
I like that you made the movies longer .
They 're better this way .